Jérôme Journot

7475 rue Tunisie

Brossard, QC J4W 2J3

Phone: 514 560 4202

E-Mail: jeromejournot@gmail.com

Profile Summary

An inspiring Lead Software Developer with over 10 years of experience, focusing on enabling team mates and design solutions that generate business value. Extensive knowledge and understanding in software development, ecommerce, predictive analytics, and service-oriented architectures.

Technical Proficiencies

Certifications: Spring Core 3.2, Professional Scrum Master (PSM I), MongoDB for Java Developer.

Technologies: Java, Golang, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, XML, SQL, PL/SQL.

Tools and Libraries: Spring, Vertx, Maven, GIT, Docker, Kubernetes, Angular, Hazelcast, MongoDB, Eclipse, IntelliJ, Hibernate,

JPA, JIRA, JSF, ICEfaces, RichFaces, GWT, Ant, Subversion/SVN, Robot Framework.

Databases: CosmosDB, AzureDB, SQL Server, MySQL, LDAP, Access.

Servers JEE: Tomcat, WebLogic, JBoss.

Education

Master II Information Systems, Grenoble IAE (2 years)	2007
DUETI / BSc European Engineering Business Management, Coventry (1 Year)	2004
DUT Mechanical Engineering, Dijon IUT (2 years)	2003

Experience

Lead Software Developer R&D

SAP - Montreal

Aug. 2012 – Today

A software company that sells enterprise multichannel ecommerce and product content management software, above all, a great technology company focusing on solutions for customer engagement and commerce.

- Lead Developer for various projects over time: SAP suite orchestration framework, Saas Commerce Cloud and the Order Management System
- Close collaboration with product owner and scrum master to manage priorities efficiently.
- Extensive involvement in the full life-cycle of the software development process, including requirements, design, coding, testing, reviewing, debugging and maintenance. Provided new solutions to improve this process.
- Supported clients in the high-level understanding of the software and interpreting their needs in order to find the required solutions.
- Innovative designs and proof of concept development for disruptive solutions.
- Full stack features development.
- Team mentoring to help each individual to reach his full potential.
- Analyzed and automated tests for the integration of new features in the Hybris platform.
- Provided detailed documentation on how to extend our product through comprehensive examples.

Java, Golang, Spring, vertX, REST, GraphQL, Docker, Kubernetes, Maven, Junit, IntelliJ, GIT, Jenkins

Lead Software Developer for European Commission KITRY Consulting - Luxembourg

June 2011 – Apr. 2012

An IT services company in computer engineering, with nearly 20 years of experience. KITRY GROUP develops in close collaboration with its customers the best innovative and customized solutions.

- Lead Developer on the EUROSTAT application which is used to register geographic information across Europe.
- Meeting with the end customer, get early feedback from live demo and prioritize his potential change requests.
- Designed and optimized the back-end data validation according to defined business rules.
- Designed and developed front-end forms to facilitate data registration for end users.
- Provided documentation for a variety of audiences (functional and technical specifications, user guide and installation manual).
- High Level support for the software in every country.

Lead Software Developer Java/J2EE

Mar. 2010 - June 2011

Objet Direct - Lyon

An IT services company specialized in different fields such as computer engineering, training and consulting. Experts in object oriented architecture, web oriented design applications, mobile applications, and agile methodologies.

Lead Developer on the Accommodation Management Project

- Scrum Master and Lead Developer on the accommodation management software.
- Designed and developed functional JSF components to be reused by an outsourced team in Spain.
- Provided support, documentation, and knowledge transfer to the outsourced team.

Java, JEE, JSF, RichFaces, Struts, Tomcat, Oracle, Eclipse, Subversion

Lead Developer on HR Management Project

- Designed and implemented new functionalities on HR management software.
- Supported and maintained the software by prioritizing upcoming bugs.
- Involved in code reviews and code refactoring to improve and optimize the product.
- Delivered technical documentation and user guides.

Java, JEE, GWT, Hibernate, Struts, Tomcat, Eclipse, JUnit, Subversion, Mantis, Ant, Oracle, SQLServer

Software Developer Java – functional Lead Astek – Lyon

Dec. 2007 - Dec. 2009

An IT service company, with technical and operational expertise in all the engineer fields specialized in consulting, information systems, scientific and technical engineering and facilities management

- Key contributor in the evolution of the SNCF directory using Calendra from BMC Software.
- In depth involvement in functional analysis and requirements documentation.
- Evaluated technical feasibility and provided estimates.
- Improved end user experience by providing a user interface made with Swing to simplify script execution.
- Creation of a delivery process based on Apache ANT.
- Implemented an SSO authentication process based on Kerberos and secured by SSL protocol.

Java, Eclipse, WebLogic, Swing, JSP, JUnit, XML, CSS, ANT, LDAP, Calendra, SSL, QuickTestPro, LoadRunner, SVN, VSS

Software Developer PHP

Sopra – Grenoble

May 2007 - Sept. 2007

An IT software company specialized in build high performance solutions on the fields of banking and finance, human resources, and property management.

- Development on an accommodation management system following quality standards and good practices.
- Highly involved in brainstorming to find out the best solution to achieve required business needs.
- Execution of load testing using OpenSTA, targeting, and re-engineering to increase the performance of the application.

PHP5, MySQL, JavaScript, CSS, OpenSTA, Apache, Linux

Project Manager Assistant

Hewlett-Packard - Grenoble

May 2006 – Sept. 2006

HP provides hardware, software and services to consumers, small- and medium-sized businesses and large enterprises, including customers in the government, health and education sectors.

- Followed up on the planning and project management of the "SmartChoice" application (online computer customization) in an international environment.
- Improved and ran testing plans to validate business requirements.